<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>El Khalidi</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/</link><description>Recent content on El Khalidi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copy, _right?_ :thinking_face:</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elkhalidi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linux File System: A comprehensive guide</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/linux-file-system/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/linux-file-system/</guid><description>I wanted to write this Linux file system guide to clarify the logic behind file organization in Linux, aiming to empower readers to navigate and manage their systems more effectively.</description></item><item><title>Mastering SQL for Data Scientists: A Comprehensive Guide</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/mastering-sql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/mastering-sql/</guid><description>Welcome, fellow data aficionados! Prepare to embark on a thrilling expedition through the realm of SQL mastery. In this enlightening blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll unveil the fascinating journey I&amp;rsquo;ve undertaken as a data scientist, delving deep into the intricacies of SQL. Join me as I navigate the winding pathways of SELECT statements, the enchanting world of JOINs, and the powerful magic of GROUP BY and aggregation functions. From the humble beginnings of data querying to the mastery of advanced techniques like window functions and performance optimization, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through each step of the way. Get ready to unlock the secrets of SQL and empower your data analysis endeavors like never before!</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://elkhalidi.com/posts/mastering-sql/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/about/</guid><description>Hey there! 👋 I&amp;rsquo;m El Khalidi, a seasoned data scientist with a burning passion for programming. With a robust background in mathematics and statistics, backed by a BSc in Economics and an MSc in Actuarial Science, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent years delving into the intricacies of data analysis and predictive modeling.</description></item><item><title>Purism Is In Big Trouble. Talks of Insolvency &amp; Not Honoring Refunds.</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/purism-is-not-good/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/purism-is-not-good/</guid><description>Purism manufactures the Librem personal computing devices with a focus on software freedom, computer security, and internet privacy. Apparently they are struggling to still get their Librem 5 in peoples hands. They are ignoring people, and ignoring their requests for refunds.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://elkhalidi.com/posts/purism-is-not-good/feature.avif"/></item><item><title>A Polite Request for Linux Compatibility and Steam Deck Support for Deadside</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/deadside-linux-request/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/deadside-linux-request/</guid><description>I am writing on behalf of the Linux and Steam Deck gaming community to kindly request your consideration for two significant developments: Linux compatibility and Steam Deck support for Deadside.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://elkhalidi.com/posts/deadside-linux-request/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>How To Install Hugo, Add A Theme, &amp; Deploy to GitLab Pages</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/install-hugo-and-deploy-to-gitlab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/install-hugo-and-deploy-to-gitlab/</guid><description>I have had such a wonderful time using Hugo and I really do enjoy all of the things it allows me to do with ease. Even though there are plenty of fantastic guides for installing and configuring Hugo, I wanted to try my hand. Most guides or tutorials out there focus on deploying to Github or just don&amp;rsquo;t cover the topic at all.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://elkhalidi.com/posts/install-hugo-and-deploy-to-gitlab/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/projects/</guid><description>I try to stay busy learning new skills and the best way to do that is to make something. These are my projects that I am working on or have finished.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/resume/</guid><description>Experience Company Role Dates Summary Amazon Business Insights Analyst Feb 2020 - Feb 2024 Saved £850k annually by restructuring shift schedules for IT teams based on analysis results. Reduced operational expenditure by 27% through targeted spending analysis.</description></item><item><title>Why I Opted For Hugo For My New Website</title><link>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-choose-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-choose-hugo/</guid><description>I want to shed some light on why I chose Hugo for the new website here and the reasons behind my decision to transition to this robust static site generator. I have been putting off Hugo as I wanted to get better at writing my own CSS from scratch. Now that I have given it a try, I cannot believe I waited so long!</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-choose-hugo/feature.jpg"/></item></channel></rss>