<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>El Khalidi</title><link>elkhalidi.com/</link><description>Recent content on El Khalidi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copy, _right?_ :thinking_face:</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="elkhalidi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>elkhalidi.com/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/about/</guid><description>My name is Tyler 👋, but I go by Zaney online. I have been using Linux for years now and really enjoy what the ecosystem has to offer. I create videos on my experience with Linux, share my configuration files, and try to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with anyone in the community.</description></item><item><title>Purism Is In Big Trouble. Talks of Insolvency &amp; Not Honoring Refunds.</title><link>elkhalidi.com/posts/purism-is-not-good/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/posts/purism-is-not-good/</guid><description>Purism manufactures the Librem personal computing devices with a focus on software freedom, computer security, and internet privacy. Apparently they are struggling to still get their Librem 5 in peoples hands. They are ignoring people, and ignoring their requests for refunds.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/elkhalidi.com/posts/purism-is-not-good/feature.avif"/></item><item><title>A Polite Request for Linux Compatibility and Steam Deck Support for Deadside</title><link>elkhalidi.com/posts/deadside-linux-request/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/posts/deadside-linux-request/</guid><description>I am writing on behalf of the Linux and Steam Deck gaming community to kindly request your consideration for two significant developments: Linux compatibility and Steam Deck support for Deadside.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/elkhalidi.com/posts/deadside-linux-request/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>How To Install Hugo, Add A Theme, &amp; Deploy to GitLab Pages</title><link>elkhalidi.com/posts/install-hugo-and-deploy-to-gitlab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/posts/install-hugo-and-deploy-to-gitlab/</guid><description>I have had such a wonderful time using Hugo and I really do enjoy all of the things it allows me to do with ease. Even though there are plenty of fantastic guides for installing and configuring Hugo, I wanted to try my hand. Most guides or tutorials out there focus on deploying to Github or just don&amp;rsquo;t cover the topic at all.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/elkhalidi.com/posts/install-hugo-and-deploy-to-gitlab/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>elkhalidi.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/projects/</guid><description>I try to stay busy learning new skills and the best way to do that is to make something. These are my projects that I am working on or have finished.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>elkhalidi.com/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/resume/</guid><description>Experience Company Role Dates Summary Amazon Business Insights Analyst Feb 2020 - Present Conducted an analysis that led to a change of shift structure for all the IT teams across the UK, resulting in annual savings of £850k.</description></item><item><title>Why I Moved from PCManFM to Thunar</title><link>elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-moved-to-thunar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-moved-to-thunar/</guid><description>I want to dive into a change I recently made in my Linux setup that might surprise a few of you. I&amp;rsquo;ve switched from PCManFM to Thunar as my file manager.First off, PCManFM has been a solid companion on my Linux journey. It&amp;rsquo;s lightweight, fast, and offers a great set of features. However, as I delved deeper into tweaking my workflow and optimizing my system, I found myself gravitating towards Thunar for a few key reasons.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-moved-to-thunar/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>Why I Opted For Hugo For My New Website</title><link>elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-choose-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-choose-hugo/</guid><description>I want to shed some light on why I chose Hugo for the new website here and the reasons behind my decision to transition to this robust static site generator. I have been putting off Hugo as I wanted to get better at writing my own CSS from scratch. Now that I have given it a try, I cannot believe I waited so long!</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/elkhalidi.com/posts/why-i-choose-hugo/feature.jpg"/></item></channel></rss>